<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MSNE Blog</title>
    <link>https://msne2016.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on MSNE Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Powered by [Hugo](//gohugo.io). Theme by [PPOffice](http://github.com/ppoffice).</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://msne2016.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>MSNE team &#39;Neuruns&#39; at the ENB EliteCup 2017</title>
      <link>https://msne2016.github.io/2017/06/10/msne-team-neuruns-at-the-enb-elitecup-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://msne2016.github.io/2017/06/10/msne-team-neuruns-at-the-enb-elitecup-2017/</guid>
      <description>The ENB EliteCup 2017 is a football tournament between the master programs of the Elite Network of Bavaria that takes place every year. This year, we jumped at the opportunity to participate and assembled a neuroengineering team, called &amp;lsquo;The Neuruns&amp;rsquo;.
Despite the odds of being still a very small program and some of us not being able to play due to Ramadan, we managed to form a team of sufficiently many players.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring 2017 MSNE Retreat</title>
      <link>https://msne2016.github.io/2017/05/14/spring-2017-msne-retreat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://msne2016.github.io/2017/05/14/spring-2017-msne-retreat/</guid>
      <description>The Spring 2017 MSNE Retreat took place in Fischen, Allgäu from May 14 to May 17.
Apart from the MSNE Students, we welcomed the following speakers for invited talks:
 Thursday: Prof. Dr. Matthias Bethge, Bethge Lab, University of Tübingen Friday: Prof. Dr. Heiko Neumann, Institut für Neuroinformatik, University of Ulm Saturday: Dr. Dmitry Kireev, Institute of Bioelectronics, Forschungszentrum Jülich  Retreat Proceedings Proceedings of the retreat are available here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Participation in the Munich Brain Course</title>
      <link>https://msne2016.github.io/2017/04/01/participation-in-the-munich-brain-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://msne2016.github.io/2017/04/01/participation-in-the-munich-brain-course/</guid>
      <description>After a semester of interesting theoretical lectures in neuroanatomy and neurophysiology we had the chance of gaining practical hands-on experience about the human brain in the Munich Brain Course.
The Munich Brain Course is a yearly intensive course on neuroanatomy organized by the Institute of Anatomy of the Ludwig Maximilians University (LMU) - the non-technical university in Munich.
The course started in the morning with a nice welcome buffet. Strengthened by the snacks and the coffee, we learned about the century-long history of neuroscience research in Munich and about the structure and organization of the course during an introductory talk and then had the pleasure to hear from Prof.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1st Human Brain Project student conference in Vienna</title>
      <link>https://msne2016.github.io/2017/02/10/1st-human-brain-project-student-conference-in-vienna/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://msne2016.github.io/2017/02/10/1st-human-brain-project-student-conference-in-vienna/</guid>
      <description>In February, Raja, Abdallah, James and Nicolas had the chance to attend the first student conference of the European Human Brain Project in Vienna. This study trip was carried out within the MSNE program and was supported by the Elite Network of Barvaria (ENB).
Having already brought our suitcases to the final exam in Computational Neuroscience, we started our trip directly after handing in our solutions. Late in the evening, after a four-hour train ride, we finally arrived in Vienna and checked in at our hotel which was in walking distance to the university of Vienna where the conference was hosted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christkindl Market</title>
      <link>https://msne2016.github.io/2016/12/09/christkindl-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://msne2016.github.io/2016/12/09/christkindl-market/</guid>
      <description>On Dec. 9th we met with the MSNE program manager, Florian Rattei, at one of the many Christkindl-Markets in Munich for some nice hot Glühwein.
The medival-themed market with its many craftsmen and -women including a glassblower, a goldsmith and calligraphers as well as the authentic wooden stalls immediately makes one forget the stressful daily routine and emits a traditional Christmassy atmosphere.
Standing around a stump that served as a table for our Glühwein cups, we also talked about organisational matters and planned activities like the writing of this blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to our blog!</title>
      <link>https://msne2016.github.io/2016/09/23/welcome-to-our-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://msne2016.github.io/2016/09/23/welcome-to-our-blog/</guid>
      <description>We are students from the Master of Science program in Neuroengineering (MSNE) at the Technical University in Munich and are using this site to share our experiences.
This blog serves two purposes:
 We want to write a diary about the many great things that we are doing and experiencing. The blog is also supposed to give information to students interested in joining the program.  Disclaimer: This is a personal blog by the students in the Neuroengineering program and not an official website by TUM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://msne2016.github.io/impressum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://msne2016.github.io/impressum/</guid>
      <description>Nicolas Berberich
Mitterweg 21 85478 Garching
n.berberich@gmail.com
Impressum: Angaben gemäß § 5 TMG.
Haftung für Inhalte
Als Diensteanbieter sind wir gemäß § 7 Abs.1 TMG für eigene Inhalte auf diesen Seiten nach den allgemeinen Gesetzen verantwortlich. Nach §§ 8 bis 10 TMG sind wir als Diensteanbieter jedoch nicht verpflichtet, übermittelte oder gespeicherte fremde Informationen zu überwachen oder nach Umständen zu forschen, die auf eine rechtswidrige Tätigkeit hinweisen.
Verpflichtungen zur Entfernung oder Sperrung der Nutzung von Informationen nach den allgemeinen Gesetzen bleiben hiervon unberührt.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>