<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Events on MSNE Blog</title>
    <link>https://neuroengineering.blog/tags/events/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Events on MSNE Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://neuroengineering.blog/tags/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Farewell for Prof. Jörg Conradt</title>
      <link>https://neuroengineering.blog/2018/07/04/farewell-for-prof.-j%C3%B6rg-conradt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neuroengineering.blog/2018/07/04/farewell-for-prof.-j%C3%B6rg-conradt/</guid>
      <description>As our co-director Prof. Jörg Conradt will be moving to KTH (Sweden) in August to build up a research group there, Auguste and I organized a farewell party for him. With support from the Institute for Electrical Energy Storage Technology, we set up a bunch of tables in the backyard of the Karlsstraße university building and everyone of us neuroengineering students brought some food. Mirroring the diversity of our nationalities we had a plethora of tasty dishes, from Bavarian brezels and Italian caprese salad to great eastern dishes that I can&amp;rsquo;t remember the names of.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RobotCare - Future of Care between Human and Machine</title>
      <link>https://neuroengineering.blog/2018/07/02/robotcare---future-of-care-between-human-and-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neuroengineering.blog/2018/07/02/robotcare---future-of-care-between-human-and-machine/</guid>
      <description>Once we grow old, will we still be cared for by humans or will robots have taken over?
According to Science and Technology Studies (STS) this is the wrong question to ask. There is no technological determinism - the course of technological development is not written in stone - we humans have the ultimate say in the matter of what becomes reality and what doesn&amp;rsquo;t, or at least we can play a role in the complex interplay of social and technical factors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conference on Clinical Neurotechnologies and Healthy Aging</title>
      <link>https://neuroengineering.blog/2018/06/27/conference-on-clinical-neurotechnologies-and-healthy-aging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neuroengineering.blog/2018/06/27/conference-on-clinical-neurotechnologies-and-healthy-aging/</guid>
      <description>In June, Nicolas and I made our way to Tübingen to attend the German-Israeli Conference on Clinical Neurotechnologies and Healthy Aging.
The focus lay on brain stimulation which could even be tested during the coffee breaks (I prefer not to show the video of my involuntarily kicking legs here). When speaking of the &amp;lsquo;brain&amp;rsquo; the retina is also meant (of course).
On the last day the MedTech Startup School offered an Open Innovation Day where we discussed several aspects of founding a Neuro-Tech start-up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSNE Journal Club</title>
      <link>https://neuroengineering.blog/2018/06/24/msne-journal-club/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neuroengineering.blog/2018/06/24/msne-journal-club/</guid>
      <description>Science communication is an essential aspect of scientific research. It enables scientists and researchers to inform each other, as well as the public, about science progress and invoke scientific, political and ethical thinking. The general purpose of a journal club is to facilitate the review of research studies and to discuss implications of the study in practice. In general, a journal club helps with:
 Sharing knowledge of current research Facilitating the learning process Enhancing literature critique and appraisal skills Encouraging interaction and dialogue with other researchers Encouraging research utilization, and Promoting team building  During the course of our master program, we have two mandatory discussion seminar blocks, which are very helpful in training us with the above mentioned traits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSNE team &#39;Neuruns&#39; at the ENB EliteCup 2018</title>
      <link>https://neuroengineering.blog/2018/06/09/msne-team-neuruns-at-the-enb-elitecup-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neuroengineering.blog/2018/06/09/msne-team-neuruns-at-the-enb-elitecup-2018/</guid>
      <description>Saturday the 9th of June was witness of another edition of the ENB Elite Cup. The Neuruns took part in it again, with two batches together adding up to the might of the team in what was an epic day in the history of sports.
The neurons arrived in the early morning to warm up and define the new positions for the team. Starring were Georges, Jonas, Michael, Janne, Nicolas, Auguste, Elisa, Francisco, Mohammad and Lucas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2nd MSNE Retreat</title>
      <link>https://neuroengineering.blog/2018/06/01/2nd-msne-retreat/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neuroengineering.blog/2018/06/01/2nd-msne-retreat/</guid>
      <description>The Spring 2018 MSNE Retreat took place in Ofterschwang, Allgäu from May 31 to June 3.
Apart from thirty participating first and second year MSNE Students, we welcomed the following speakers for invited talks:
 Thursday: Prof. Dr. Jakob Macke, Macke Lab Lab, Technical University of Munich. Friday: Prof. Dr. Benjamin Grewe, Institute of Neuroinformatics, ETH Zurich. Saturday: Prof. Dr. Thomas Euler, Institute for Opthalmic Research, University of Tübingen.  A detailed post about the retreat will follow soon!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CoC Neuro-Engineering Networking Workshop</title>
      <link>https://neuroengineering.blog/2018/04/19/coc-neuro-engineering-networking-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neuroengineering.blog/2018/04/19/coc-neuro-engineering-networking-workshop/</guid>
      <description>This April, first and second year students as well as faculty members of the MSNE met at the Networking Workshop of TU Munich&amp;rsquo;s Center of Competence in Neuroengineering.
Event agenda 14:00 Introductory remarks by Prof. Gordon Cheng Chair for Cognitive Systems (TUM)
14:10-14:30 Prof. Ilona Grunwald Kadow Neuronal Circuits and Metabolism, School of Life Sciences Weihenstephan (TUM) &amp;ldquo;Asking the fly to reveal neural network principles underlying behavior&amp;rdquo;
14:30-14:50 Prof. Markus Ploner Heisenberg Professor of Human Pain Research, Department of Neurology, School of Medicine (TUM) &amp;ldquo;Neuroengineering approaches to the understanding, diagnosis and therapy of pain&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interdisciplinary College 2018</title>
      <link>https://neuroengineering.blog/2018/03/13/interdisciplinary-college-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neuroengineering.blog/2018/03/13/interdisciplinary-college-2018/</guid>
      <description>From 9th to 16th March, MSNE students Auguste, Pranshul, Steffen and Nicolas attended the Interdisciplinary College (IK) in Günne. Since 1997, this annual spring school brings together students and researchers from the fields of computational neuroscience, neuroscience, artificial intelligence, robotics, cognitive sciences and philosophy.
The overall topic of this year Me, Myself and I was approached from various different angles through the lenses of the different scientific disciplines.
Among many other lectures, we enthusiastically attended the lecture series of MSNE faculty Prof.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2nd HBP Student Conference - Transdisciplinary Research Linking Neuroscience, Brain Medicine and Computer Science</title>
      <link>https://neuroengineering.blog/2018/02/14/2nd-hbp-student-conference---transdisciplinary-research-linking-neuroscience-brain-medicine-and-computer-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neuroengineering.blog/2018/02/14/2nd-hbp-student-conference---transdisciplinary-research-linking-neuroscience-brain-medicine-and-computer-science/</guid>
      <description>The 2nd HBP Student Conference took place in Ljubljana, Slowenia, from 14 to 16 February 2018 and and offered a rich program covering different aspects of Neuroscience and Computational Methods within Neuroscience.
Apart from invited talks, MSc and PhD students got the opportunity to present both original and ongoing research in four oral and two poster sessions, comprised of the topics
 Neurorobotics, Neuromorphic Computing, Theoretical Neuroscience Medical Informatics High Performance Computing, Brain Simulation Human Brain/Mouse Brain Organisation, Systems and Cognitive Neuroscience  Wednesday: Arrival, Neurorobotics and Kickoff I particularly perceived the conference as an effort of bringing together scientists from neuroscience and computer science and as an effort to improve communication between the fields and enhance mutual understanding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Entrepreneurship in Neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://neuroengineering.blog/2017/10/23/entrepreneurship-in-neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neuroengineering.blog/2017/10/23/entrepreneurship-in-neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>While walking through the aisles on a train to Heidelberg, I finally stumble upon my reserved seat&amp;hellip; Only to find it and its neighbors are surrounded by a family of 20. Rather than making a fuss - I go ahead and choose an unoccupied seat farther back, hoping to get some sleep in preparation for what I&amp;rsquo;m imagining will be a long three days. At the next stop, I&amp;rsquo;m roused awake by somebody asking in a distinct American accent &amp;ldquo;Is this seat available?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSNE Welcome Event</title>
      <link>https://neuroengineering.blog/2017/10/20/msne-welcome-event/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neuroengineering.blog/2017/10/20/msne-welcome-event/</guid>
      <description>With the start of the semester, 23 new students joined the Master&amp;rsquo;s program in Neuroengineering at TU Munich. This Friday, the first and second year MSNE students met for a first get-together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>13th Bernstein Conference, Göttingen</title>
      <link>https://neuroengineering.blog/2017/07/14/13th-bernstein-conference-g%C3%B6ttingen/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neuroengineering.blog/2017/07/14/13th-bernstein-conference-g%C3%B6ttingen/</guid>
      <description>This september we visited the 13th Bernstein Conference organized by the Bernstein Center for Computational Neuroscience Göttingen (BCCN Göttingen) in Göttingen.
Posters by NST Faculty and MSNE students  Tayeb Z, Erçelik E, Conradt J (2017) Decoding of EEG Brain Signals using Spiking Neural Networks on SpiNNaker Neuromorphic Hardware. Bernstein Conference 2017. doi: 10.12751/nncn.bc2017.0100 Widderich C, Everding L, Richter C, Conradt J (2017) A Cooperative Stereo Matching Neural Network on TrueNorth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSNE team &#39;Neuruns&#39; at the ENB EliteCup 2017</title>
      <link>https://neuroengineering.blog/2017/06/10/msne-team-neuruns-at-the-enb-elitecup-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neuroengineering.blog/2017/06/10/msne-team-neuruns-at-the-enb-elitecup-2017/</guid>
      <description>The ENB EliteCup 2017 is a football tournament between the master programs of the Elite Network of Bavaria that takes place every year. This year, we jumped at the opportunity to participate and assembled a neuroengineering team, called &amp;lsquo;The Neuruns&amp;rsquo;.
Despite the odds of being still a very small program and some of us not being able to play due to Ramadan, we managed to form a team of sufficiently many players.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring 2017 MSNE Retreat</title>
      <link>https://neuroengineering.blog/2017/05/14/spring-2017-msne-retreat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neuroengineering.blog/2017/05/14/spring-2017-msne-retreat/</guid>
      <description>The Spring 2017 MSNE Retreat took place in Fischen, Allgäu from May 14 to May 17.
Apart from the MSNE Students, we welcomed the following speakers for invited talks:
 Thursday: Prof. Dr. Matthias Bethge, Bethge Lab, University of Tübingen Friday: Prof. Dr. Heiko Neumann, Institut für Neuroinformatik, University of Ulm Saturday: Dr. Dmitry Kireev, Institute of Bioelectronics, Forschungszentrum Jülich  Retreat Proceedings Proceedings of the retreat are available here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Participation in the Munich Brain Course</title>
      <link>https://neuroengineering.blog/2017/04/01/participation-in-the-munich-brain-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neuroengineering.blog/2017/04/01/participation-in-the-munich-brain-course/</guid>
      <description>After a semester of interesting theoretical lectures in neuroanatomy and neurophysiology we had the chance of gaining practical hands-on experience about the human brain in the Munich Brain Course.
The Munich Brain Course is a yearly intensive course on neuroanatomy organized by the Institute of Anatomy of the Ludwig Maximilians University (LMU) - the non-technical university in Munich.
The course started in the morning with a nice welcome buffet. Strengthened by the snacks and the coffee, we learned about the century-long history of neuroscience research in Munich and about the structure and organization of the course during an introductory talk and then had the pleasure to hear from Prof.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1st Human Brain Project student conference in Vienna</title>
      <link>https://neuroengineering.blog/2017/02/10/1st-human-brain-project-student-conference-in-vienna/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neuroengineering.blog/2017/02/10/1st-human-brain-project-student-conference-in-vienna/</guid>
      <description>In February, Raja, Abdallah, James and Nicolas had the chance to attend the first student conference of the European Human Brain Project in Vienna. This study trip was carried out within the MSNE program and was supported by the Elite Network of Barvaria (ENB).
Having already brought our suitcases to the final exam in Computational Neuroscience, we started our trip directly after handing in our solutions. Late in the evening, after a four-hour train ride, we finally arrived in Vienna and checked in at our hotel which was in walking distance to the university of Vienna where the conference was hosted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christkindl Market</title>
      <link>https://neuroengineering.blog/2016/12/09/christkindl-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neuroengineering.blog/2016/12/09/christkindl-market/</guid>
      <description>On Dec. 9th we met with the MSNE program manager, Florian Rattei, at one of the many Christkindl-Markets in Munich for some nice hot Glühwein.
The medival-themed market with its many craftsmen and -women including a glassblower, a goldsmith and calligraphers as well as the authentic wooden stalls immediately makes one forget the stressful daily routine and emits a traditional Christmassy atmosphere.
Standing around a stump that served as a table for our Glühwein cups, we also talked about organisational matters and planned activities like the writing of this blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to our blog!</title>
      <link>https://neuroengineering.blog/2016/09/23/welcome-to-our-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neuroengineering.blog/2016/09/23/welcome-to-our-blog/</guid>
      <description>We are students from the Master of Science program in Neuroengineering (MSNE) at the Technical University in Munich and are using this site to share our experiences.
This blog serves two purposes:
 We want to write a diary about the many great things that we are doing and experiencing. The blog is also supposed to give information to students interested in joining the program.  Disclaimer: This is a personal blog by the students in the Neuroengineering program and not an official website by TUM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSNE Students</title>
      <link>https://neuroengineering.blog/2010/01/01/msne-students/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neuroengineering.blog/2010/01/01/msne-students/</guid>
      <description>.card { box-shadow: 0 4px 8px 0 rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.4); width:50%; height: 350px; max-width:200px; margin: 10px 5px; text-align: center; background-color: #f5f5f5; padding: 5px 5px 5px 5px; float: left; } card.col1 { float: left; width: 20%; } card.col2 { float: left; width: 70%; } card.title { font-size: 100pt; } a.link { text-decoration: none; font-size: 18px; } .image-cropper { width: 100px; height: 100px; margin: 10px auto; position: relative; overflow: hidden; border-radius: 50%; } img { display: inline; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; height: 100%; width: 100%; margin: 0 auto;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>