<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Events on MSNE Blog</title>
    <link>https://msne2016.github.io/tags/events/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Events on MSNE Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://msne2016.github.io/tags/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>CoC Neuro-Engineering Networking Workshop</title>
      <link>https://msne2016.github.io/2018/04/19/coc-neuro-engineering-networking-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://msne2016.github.io/2018/04/19/coc-neuro-engineering-networking-workshop/</guid>
      <description>This April, first and second year students as well as faculty members of the MSNE met at the Networking Workshop of TU Munich&amp;rsquo;s Center of Competence in Neuroengineering.
Event agenda 14:00 Introductory remarks by Prof. Gordon Cheng Chair for Cognitive Systems (TUM)
14:10-14:30 Prof. Ilona Grunwald Kadow Neuronal Circuits and Metabolism, School of Life Sciences Weihenstephan (TUM) &amp;ldquo;Asking the fly to reveal neural network principles underlying behavior&amp;rdquo;
14:30-14:50 Prof. Markus Ploner Heisenberg Professor of Human Pain Research, Department of Neurology, School of Medicine (TUM) &amp;ldquo;Neuroengineering approaches to the understanding, diagnosis and therapy of pain&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interdisciplinary College 2018</title>
      <link>https://msne2016.github.io/2018/03/13/interdisciplinary-college-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://msne2016.github.io/2018/03/13/interdisciplinary-college-2018/</guid>
      <description>From 9th to 16th March, MSNE students Auguste, Pranshul, Steffen and Nicolas attended the Interdisciplinary College (IK) in Günne. Since 1997, this annual spring school brings together students and researchers from the fields of computational neuroscience, neuroscience, artificial intelligence, robotics, cognitive sciences and philosophy.
The overall topic of this year Me, Myself and I was approached from various different angles through the lenses of the different scientific disciplines.
Among many other lectures, we enthusiastically attended the lecture series of MSNE faculty Prof.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2nd HBP Student Conference - Transdisciplinary Research Linking Neuroscience, Brain Medicine and Computer Science</title>
      <link>https://msne2016.github.io/2018/02/14/2nd-hbp-student-conference---transdisciplinary-research-linking-neuroscience-brain-medicine-and-computer-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://msne2016.github.io/2018/02/14/2nd-hbp-student-conference---transdisciplinary-research-linking-neuroscience-brain-medicine-and-computer-science/</guid>
      <description>The 2nd HBP Student Conference took place in Ljubljana, Slowenia, from 14 to 16 February 2018 and and offered a rich program covering different aspects of Neuroscience and Computational Methods within Neuroscience.
Apart from invited talks, MSc and PhD students got the opportunity to present both original and ongoing research in four oral and two poster sessions, comprised of the topics
 Neurorobotics, Neuromorphic Computing, Theoretical Neuroscience Medical Informatics High Performance Computing, Brain Simulation Human Brain/Mouse Brain Organisation, Systems and Cognitive Neuroscience  Wednesday: Arrival, Neurorobotics and Kickoff I particularly perceived the conference as an effort of bringing together scientists from neuroscience and computer science and as an effort to improve communication between the fields and enhance mutual understanding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Entrepreneurship in Neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://msne2016.github.io/2017/10/23/entrepreneurship-in-neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://msne2016.github.io/2017/10/23/entrepreneurship-in-neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>While walking through the aisles on a train to Heidelberg, I finally stumble upon my reserved seat&amp;hellip; Only to find it and its neighbors are surrounded by a family of 20. Rather than making a fuss - I go ahead and choose an unoccupied seat farther back, hoping to get some sleep in preparation for what I&amp;rsquo;m imagining will be a long three days. At the next stop, I&amp;rsquo;m roused awake by somebody asking in a distinct American accent &amp;ldquo;Is this seat available?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSNE Welcome Event</title>
      <link>https://msne2016.github.io/2017/10/20/msne-welcome-event/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://msne2016.github.io/2017/10/20/msne-welcome-event/</guid>
      <description>With the start of the semester, 23 new students joined the Master&amp;rsquo;s program in Neuroengineering at TU Munich. This Friday, the first and second year MSNE students met for a first get-together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>13th Bernstein Conference, Göttingen</title>
      <link>https://msne2016.github.io/2017/07/14/13th-bernstein-conference-g%C3%B6ttingen/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://msne2016.github.io/2017/07/14/13th-bernstein-conference-g%C3%B6ttingen/</guid>
      <description>This september we visited the 13th Bernstein Conference organized by the Bernstein Center for Computational Neuroscience Göttingen (BCCN Göttingen) in Göttingen.
Posters by NST Faculty and MSNE students  Tayeb Z, Erçelik E, Conradt J (2017) Decoding of EEG Brain Signals using Spiking Neural Networks on SpiNNaker Neuromorphic Hardware. Bernstein Conference 2017. doi: 10.12751/nncn.bc2017.0100 Widderich C, Everding L, Richter C, Conradt J (2017) A Cooperative Stereo Matching Neural Network on TrueNorth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSNE team &#39;Neuruns&#39; at the ENB EliteCup 2017</title>
      <link>https://msne2016.github.io/2017/06/10/msne-team-neuruns-at-the-enb-elitecup-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://msne2016.github.io/2017/06/10/msne-team-neuruns-at-the-enb-elitecup-2017/</guid>
      <description>The ENB EliteCup 2017 is a football tournament between the master programs of the Elite Network of Bavaria that takes place every year. This year, we jumped at the opportunity to participate and assembled a neuroengineering team, called &amp;lsquo;The Neuruns&amp;rsquo;.
Despite the odds of being still a very small program and some of us not being able to play due to Ramadan, we managed to form a team of sufficiently many players.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring 2017 MSNE Retreat</title>
      <link>https://msne2016.github.io/2017/05/14/spring-2017-msne-retreat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://msne2016.github.io/2017/05/14/spring-2017-msne-retreat/</guid>
      <description>The Spring 2017 MSNE Retreat took place in Fischen, Allgäu from May 14 to May 17.
Apart from the MSNE Students, we welcomed the following speakers for invited talks:
 Thursday: Prof. Dr. Matthias Bethge, Bethge Lab, University of Tübingen Friday: Prof. Dr. Heiko Neumann, Institut für Neuroinformatik, University of Ulm Saturday: Dr. Dmitry Kireev, Institute of Bioelectronics, Forschungszentrum Jülich  Retreat Proceedings Proceedings of the retreat are available here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Participation in the Munich Brain Course</title>
      <link>https://msne2016.github.io/2017/04/01/participation-in-the-munich-brain-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://msne2016.github.io/2017/04/01/participation-in-the-munich-brain-course/</guid>
      <description>After a semester of interesting theoretical lectures in neuroanatomy and neurophysiology we had the chance of gaining practical hands-on experience about the human brain in the Munich Brain Course.
The Munich Brain Course is a yearly intensive course on neuroanatomy organized by the Institute of Anatomy of the Ludwig Maximilians University (LMU) - the non-technical university in Munich.
The course started in the morning with a nice welcome buffet. Strengthened by the snacks and the coffee, we learned about the century-long history of neuroscience research in Munich and about the structure and organization of the course during an introductory talk and then had the pleasure to hear from Prof.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1st Human Brain Project student conference in Vienna</title>
      <link>https://msne2016.github.io/2017/02/10/1st-human-brain-project-student-conference-in-vienna/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://msne2016.github.io/2017/02/10/1st-human-brain-project-student-conference-in-vienna/</guid>
      <description>In February, Raja, Abdallah, James and Nicolas had the chance to attend the first student conference of the European Human Brain Project in Vienna. This study trip was carried out within the MSNE program and was supported by the Elite Network of Barvaria (ENB).
Having already brought our suitcases to the final exam in Computational Neuroscience, we started our trip directly after handing in our solutions. Late in the evening, after a four-hour train ride, we finally arrived in Vienna and checked in at our hotel which was in walking distance to the university of Vienna where the conference was hosted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christkindl Market</title>
      <link>https://msne2016.github.io/2016/12/09/christkindl-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://msne2016.github.io/2016/12/09/christkindl-market/</guid>
      <description>On Dec. 9th we met with the MSNE program manager, Florian Rattei, at one of the many Christkindl-Markets in Munich for some nice hot Glühwein.
The medival-themed market with its many craftsmen and -women including a glassblower, a goldsmith and calligraphers as well as the authentic wooden stalls immediately makes one forget the stressful daily routine and emits a traditional Christmassy atmosphere.
Standing around a stump that served as a table for our Glühwein cups, we also talked about organisational matters and planned activities like the writing of this blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to our blog!</title>
      <link>https://msne2016.github.io/2016/09/23/welcome-to-our-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://msne2016.github.io/2016/09/23/welcome-to-our-blog/</guid>
      <description>We are students from the Master of Science program in Neuroengineering (MSNE) at the Technical University in Munich and are using this site to share our experiences.
This blog serves two purposes:
 We want to write a diary about the many great things that we are doing and experiencing. The blog is also supposed to give information to students interested in joining the program.  Disclaimer: This is a personal blog by the students in the Neuroengineering program and not an official website by TUM.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>