<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>research on The Neurogineering Blog</title>
    <link>https://neuroengineering.blog/tags/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in research on The Neurogineering Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://neuroengineering.blog/tags/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://neuroengineering.blog/about/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neuroengineering.blog/about/research/</guid>
      <description>Retreats  1st MSNE Retreat 2017. Invited Speakers: Matthias Bethge, Heiko Neumann, Dmitry Kireev 2nd MSNE Retreat 2018. Invited Speakers: Jakob Macke, Benjamin Grewe, Thomas Euler Soon: 3rd MSNE Retreat 2019  Conference Visits 2019  Computational and Systems Neuroscience 2019 (cosyne.org)  2018  13th Bernstein Conference Göttingen 2nd HBP Student Conference Interdisciplinary College CoC Neuroengineering Workshop Munich Conference on Clinical Neurotechnologies and Healthy Aging Neuroscience 2018, San Diego (sfn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSNE Research Internships in Manchester and Atlanta</title>
      <link>https://neuroengineering.blog/2019/03/09/msne-research-internships-in-manchester-and-atlanta/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neuroengineering.blog/2019/03/09/msne-research-internships-in-manchester-and-atlanta/</guid>
      <description>As a part of our Master’s program, MSNE students explore labs outside of our programs in 6 to 8 week research internships. In this and a following series of posts, we collected stories of the experiences we made during our internships. In the second post, Lucas and Jonas share their impressions from their internships in Manchester and Atlanta.
Lucas: University of Manchester, UK In the 2018 spring break, from February to April, I was part of the APT Advanced Processor Technologies Research Group at the University of Manchester.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSNE Research Internships in Californa, Tübingen and Boston</title>
      <link>https://neuroengineering.blog/2018/11/16/msne-research-internships-in-californa-t%C3%BCbingen-and-boston/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neuroengineering.blog/2018/11/16/msne-research-internships-in-californa-t%C3%BCbingen-and-boston/</guid>
      <description>As a part of our Master&#39;s program, MSNE students explore labs outside of our programs in 6 to 8 week research internships. In this and a following series of posts, we collected stories of the experiences we made during our internships. In our first post, Pranshul, Annika and Vanessa share their impressions from interning in California, Tübingen and Boston.
Pranshul: UC Davis with Dr. Clifford Saron I joined Dr. Clifford Saron’s lab at the University of California, Davis.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>