<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Abouts on The Neurogineering Blog</title>
    <link>https://neuroengineering.blog/about/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Abouts on The Neurogineering Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://neuroengineering.blog/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://neuroengineering.blog/about/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neuroengineering.blog/about/research/</guid>
      <description>Retreats  1st MSNE Retreat 2017. Invited Speakers: Matthias Bethge, Heiko Neumann, Dmitry Kireev 2nd MSNE Retreat 2018. Invited Speakers: Jakob Macke, Benjamin Grewe, Thomas Euler Soon: 3rd MSNE Retreat 2019  Conference Visits 2019  Computational and Systems Neuroscience 2019 (cosyne.org)  2018  13th Bernstein Conference Göttingen 2nd HBP Student Conference Interdisciplinary College CoC Neuroengineering Workshop Munich Conference on Clinical Neurotechnologies and Healthy Aging Neuroscience 2018, San Diego (sfn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Datenschutzerklärung</title>
      <link>https://neuroengineering.blog/about/datenschutz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neuroengineering.blog/about/datenschutz/</guid>
      <description>Datenschutzerklärung  Diese Datenschutzerklärung klärt Sie über die Art, den Umfang und Zweck der Verarbeitung von personenbezogenen Daten (nachfolgend kurz „Daten&amp;rdquo;) im Rahmen der Erbringung unserer Leistungen sowie innerhalb unseres Onlineangebotes und der mit ihm verbundenen Webseiten, Funktionen und Inhalte sowie externen Onlinepräsenzen, wie z.B. unser Social Media Profile auf (nachfolgend gemeinsam bezeichnet als „Onlineangebot&amp;rdquo;). Im Hinblick auf die verwendeten Begrifflichkeiten, wie z.B. „Verarbeitung&amp;rdquo; oder „Verantwortlicher&amp;rdquo; verweisen wir auf die Definitionen im Art.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impressium (Imprint)</title>
      <link>https://neuroengineering.blog/about/impressium/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neuroengineering.blog/about/impressium/</guid>
      <description>Stellvertretend für die Studierende des M.Sc. Neuroengineering (es handelt sich um ein Studierendenprojekt ohne direkte Zugehörigkeit zur TU München)
Steffen Schneider, Nicolas BerberichMitterweg 2185478 GarchingAdmin: steffen.schneider@tum.deLink zur Datenschutzerklärung: neuroengineering.blog/about/datenschutz
Angaben gemäß § 5 TMG.
Haftung für Inhalte Als Diensteanbieter sind wir gemäß § 7 Abs.1 TMG für eigene Inhalte auf diesen Seiten nach den allgemeinen Gesetzen verantwortlich. Nach §§ 8 bis 10 TMG sind wir als Diensteanbieter jedoch nicht verpflichtet, übermittelte oder gespeicherte fremde Informationen zu überwachen oder nach Umständen zu forschen, die auf eine rechtswidrige Tätigkeit hinweisen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journal Club</title>
      <link>https://neuroengineering.blog/about/journalclub/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neuroengineering.blog/about/journalclub/</guid>
      <description>Science communication is an essential aspect of scientific research. It enables scientists and researchers to inform each other, as well as the public, about science progress and invoke scientific, political and ethical thinking. The general purpose of a journal club is to facilitate the review of research studies and to discuss implications of the study in practice. In general, a journal club helps with:
 Sharing knowledge of current research Facilitating the learning process Enhancing literature critique and appraisal skills Encouraging interaction and dialogue with other researchers Encouraging research utilization, and Promoting team building  The Neuroengineering Journal Club (NJC) is all about the above-mentioned objectives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the MSNE Student Blog!</title>
      <link>https://neuroengineering.blog/about/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neuroengineering.blog/about/about/</guid>
      <description>We are students from the Master of Science program in Neuroengineering (MSNE) at the Technical University in Munich and are using this site to share our experiences.
This blog serves two purposes:
 We want to write a diary about the many great things that we are doing and experiencing. The blog is also supposed to give information to students interested in joining the program.  Disclaimer: This is a personal blog by the students in the Neuroengineering program and not an official website by TUM.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>