<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>social on The Neurogineering Blog</title>
    <link>https://neuroengineering.blog/tags/social/</link>
    <description>Recent content in social on The Neurogineering Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 05:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://neuroengineering.blog/tags/social/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>After our visit to the Texas Instruments headquarters in Freising. Credits: Voelkl, TI</title>
      <link>https://neuroengineering.blog/2020/03/31/after-our-visit-to-the-texas-instruments-headquarters-in-freising.-credits-voelkl-ti/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neuroengineering.blog/2020/03/31/after-our-visit-to-the-texas-instruments-headquarters-in-freising.-credits-voelkl-ti/</guid>
      <description>Hello world! We are back after a long absence with more stories to share about our student life in the MSNE program. At this point it seems appropriate to start off by introducing ourselves, the 4th batch of MSNE students.
Our cohort, just like the previous ones, comes from all around the globe: be it Brazil and South Korea, India and Italy, the US and Germany, and many, many more. What brings us together in Munich is a shared goal of defining new frontiers in neuroscience through engineering training or vice versa - using an understanding of the brain to advance in complex engineering problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neuruns v3.0 in the Elite Cup</title>
      <link>https://neuroengineering.blog/2019/06/22/neuruns-v3.0-in-the-elite-cup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neuroengineering.blog/2019/06/22/neuruns-v3.0-in-the-elite-cup/</guid>
      <description>Germany’s most awaited football tournament, the Champions’ League Elite Cup, was held on Saturday 22ndof June 2019 in Regensburg. Once again, the MSNE football team, the Neuruns, picked up the call of duty.
Despite terrible weather forecasts, which prognosed heavy storms throughout the day, the Neuruns decided to go at the last moment (literally), and so they boarded the train towards glory, with an inherited objective: score a goal and break the curse!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3rd MSNE Retreat</title>
      <link>https://neuroengineering.blog/2019/05/30/3rd-msne-retreat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neuroengineering.blog/2019/05/30/3rd-msne-retreat/</guid>
      <description>The third MSNE retreat started on 30th of May - in a very picturesque village called Brixlegg in Tyrol, Austria - and of course it couldn&amp;rsquo;t start without adventures from the beginning. We&amp;rsquo;ll try to share with you the amazing neuro-weekend we spent together.
First day First thing we remember is how Aleks, Nogay, Tanya and our awesome organizers (Mel, Fulvia and Adrià) were trying to take all the cookies and other less important things from Adrià&amp;rsquo;s place - and almost missed the bus since the driver was expecting to be leaving earlier.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
